<resources>
    <string name="app_name" translatable="false">Pasolini</string>
    <string name="app_long_name" translatable="false">Pasolini, Sguardi di Vita</string>
    <string name="text_monteverde" translatable="false">Monteverde</string>
    <string name="text_rome">Rome</string>
    <string name="text_tour">Tour</string>
    <string name="text_augmented_reality">Augmented Reality</string>

    <!-- Static content -->
    <string name="pasolini_roma_title">Pasolini and Rome</string>
    <string name="pasolini_roma_content">"Pier Paolo Pasolini in 1949 he moved to Rome, settling
        first in a township, living on private lessons and teaching in a private school. The
        discovery of the world of the Roman underclass inspired him - as well as some of the verses
        contained in the Ashes of Gramsci (1957) and in the religion of my time (1961), which
        followed those of the nightingale of the Catholic Church (but the years 1943 to 1949, ie
        prior to the Ashes) - especially the novels Ragazzi di vita (1955) and a violent life
        (1959), who made a scandal, but it started to literary success. With the old fellow
        Leonetti and Roversi university, founded and directed from 1955 to 1959 the magazine
        \"Workshop\", which saw among the collaborators Fortini, Volponi and other important
        literary critics and activists. meanwhile He began his activity in one of the film world:
        he collaborated with some screenplays (for nights of Cabiria Fellini), then from 1961 he
        directed numerous films, from Tramp to Hawks and the Sparrows, from Oedipus king Theorem,
        from Medea to the Decameron. Many of these films did scandal, like novels, and in some
        cases cost him to Pasolini trials and convictions. In the sixties he published The dream
        of a thing (a novel written in 1949), he wrote some tragedies, other verses (Poetry in the
        form of pink, 1964; Trasumanar and organizzar, 1971) and made an intense militant critic
        in various newspapers and magazines (among other things headed with Moravia and Carocci
        \"New Topics\"), an activity that, after collection Passion and ideology (1960), resulted
        in numerous books, some published posthumously: from heretical Empiricism (1972) and
        Writings corsairs (1975) in the descriptions descriptions (1979). He died assassinated in
        Ostia in obscure circumstances in 1975. "</string>
    <string name="pasolini_monteverde_title">Pasolini and Monteverde</string>
    <string name="pasolini_monteverde_content">Pier Paolo Pasolini, he moved in 1954 in Rome, in
        the Monteverde district. The partnership between Pasolini and the so-called Donna Olimpia
        is those intended to not dissolve anymore. This is witnessed in some ways, but especially
        the novel Ragazzi di vita, the first great success of the poet, published in 1955. In the
        first two chapters of the novel (the Ferrobedò, Riccetto) are continuous references to
        visions and landscapes of Monteverde. Emblematic of the relationship established between
        Pasolini, the neighborhood and its people. Relationship that has continued over time. Time
        which resulted in dramatic changes in the city, transformed by urban development often
        wild, and in the people, that with the economic well-being went slowly losing their
        authenticity and spontaneity, by acquiring the underclass, according to Pasolini, the
        narrow-mindedness of the petty bourgeois.</string>
</resources>
